noredink.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy | NoRedInk

_Effective date: April 29, 2015_

By using or accessing the Services in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways.

Remember that your use of NoRedInk's Services is at all times subject to the Terms of Use, which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Use.

If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please send a detailed message to [support@noredink.com](mailto:support@noredink.com), and we will try to resolve your concerns.

## Quick Reference##

  * What does this Privacy Policy cover?
  * Will NoRedInk ever change this Privacy Policy?
  * What Information does NoRedInk collect?
    * Information You Provide to Us
    * Information Collected Automatically
  * Will NoRedInk share any of the Personal Information it receives?
    * Usage Information
    * Affiliated Businesses
    * Agents
    * User Profiles and Submissions
    * Business Transfers
    * Protection of NoRedInk and Others
  * Is Personal Information about me secure?
  * What Personal Information can I access?
  * What choices do I have?
  * Addendum for Connecticut Users

## What does this Privacy Policy cover?

**This Privacy Policy covers how we treat personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that we gather when you are accessing or using our Services, but not to the practices of companies we don't own or control, or people that we don't manage.**

We gather various types of Personal Information from our users, as explained in more detail below, and we use this Personal Information internally in connection with our Services, including to personalize and improve our services, to allow you to set up a user account and profile, to contact you and allow other users to contact you, to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, and to analyze how you use the Services. In certain cases, we may also share some Personal Information with third parties, but only as described below under the heading "Will NoRedInk Share Any of the Personal Information It Receives?".

If you are not of legal age to form a binding contract (in many jurisdictions, this age is 18), you may only use the Services and disclose information to us with your parent's or legal guardian's express consent. Review this Privacy Policy with your parent or legal guardian to make sure you understand it.

As noted in the Terms of Use, we only collect Personal Information through the Services from a child under 13 where that student's school, district, and/or teacher has agreed (via the terms described in the Terms of Use) to obtain parental consent for that child to use the Services and disclose Personal Information to us. A parent or guardian may sign up his or her child for the Services and provide Personal Information about that child to us. However, no child under 13 may send us any Personal Information unless he or she has signed up through his or her school, district or teacher and such school, district or teacher has obtained parental consent for that child to use the Services and disclose Personal Information to us. If you are a student under 13, please do not send any Personal Information to us if your school, district, and/or teacher has not obtained this prior consent from your parent or guardian, and please do not send any Personal Information other than what we request from you in connection with the Services. If we learn we have collected Personal Information from a student under 13 without parental consent from his or her parent or guardian or obtained by his or her school, district, and/or teacher, or if we learn a student under 13 has provided us personal information beyond what we request from him or her, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a student under 13 may have provided us personal information in violation of this paragraph, please contact us at [support@noredink.com](mailto:support@noredink.com).

When we use the term “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy, we are referring to personally identifiable information of individual registrants of the Services. References to “Children's Personal Information” only apply to personally identifiable information of users who have registered for the Services as minor students (i.e., students under the age of 13). General references to “information” apply to all users.

## Will NoRedInk ever change this Privacy Policy?

**We're constantly trying to improve our Services, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time as well.**

We will alert you to material changes at least 30 days before they take effect by placing a notice on noredink.com, by sending you an email, and/or by some other means. We reserve the right, however, to effect important changes more quickly as needed, as in the case of a security threat or other emergency situation. Please note that if you've opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or you haven't provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been made effective, that means you agree to all of the changes.

## What Information does NoRedInk collect?

**This section covers two types of information: information you provide to us, and information collected automatically.**

### Information You Provide to Us:

**It is our objective to collect and store only user information you knowingly provide to us and that is reasonably necessary to operate the Services.**

We receive and store any information you knowingly provide to us. For example, through the registration process and/or through your account settings, we may collect Personal Information such as your name, email address, school affiliation and third-party account credentials (for example, login credentials for Google). If you provide third-party account credentials to us, you understand some content and/or information in those accounts (“Third Party Account Information”) may be transmitted into your account with us if you authorize such transmissions, and that Third Party Account Information transmitted to our Services is covered by this Privacy Policy; for example, if you authorize us to connect with your Google account, we may access the information on your Google account that you give us permission to access. Certain information may be required to register with us or to take advantage of some of our features. The Children's Personal Information you provide shall only be used for creating your individual account and to provide you the Services, and for sending you notifications. You may modify or remove your Personal Information identified below under the heading "What Personal Information can I access?" at any time by logging into your account and accessing features to edit your profile and/or account information. Please note that if you signed up through your school and/or district, your school and/or district can view all activity and content associated with your student account, including your Personal Information.

We may communicate with you if you've provided us the means to do so. For example, if you've given us your email address, we may email you about update to the Services. If you do not want to receive communications from us, please indicate your preference by emailing [support@noredink.com](mailto:support@noredink.com).

### Information Collected Automatically

**We collect some information automatically, as detailed below, but we never use it in a way that would identify you personally.**

Whenever you interact with our Services, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser or device, which may include your IP address, “cookie” information, the type of browser and/or device you're using to access our Services, and the page or feature you requested. “Cookies” are identifiers we transfer to your browser or device that allow us to recognize your browser or device and tell us how and when pages and features in our Services are visited and by how many people. You may be able to change the preferences on your browser or device to prevent or limit your device's acceptance of cookies, but this may prevent you from taking advantage of some of our features. If you click on a link to a third party website or service, such third party may also transmit cookies to you. Again, this Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties, and we aren't responsible for their privacy policies and practices.

When we collect the usage information described above, we only use this data in aggregate form, and not in a manner that would identify you personally. For example, this aggregate data can tell us how often users use a particular feature of the Services, and we can use that knowledge to make the Services interesting to as many users as possible.

**We won't rent or sell (including for purposes of marketing or advertising) your Personal Information in personally identifiable form to anyone.**

We may share your Personal Information with third parties for other reasons, but only as described in this section.

### Usage Information

_This section describes how we share statistical data we collect on the site._

NoRedInk uses aggregate, de-identified user data to enable us to figure out how often users use parts of the Services, so that we can customize and improve those Services. As part of our use of such information, we may provide such information to our partners (only in a de-identified format) about how our users use our site. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use our partners' services and the Services to help provide you with an optimal online experience. We may link usage information to Personal Information that we collect through the Services, but we will only use this linked information internally (for example, to customize your experience), and will not disclose it in linked format to third parties.

### Affiliated Businesses

_This section describes how we share information with companies like Facebook and Twitter._

In certain situations, businesses or third party websites we're affiliated with may provide services to you through the Services (either alone or jointly with us). You can recognize when an affiliated business is associated with such transactions or services by the display of their name and/or logo, and **we will share your Personal Information with that affiliated business only with your permission, and only to the extent that it is related to such transactions or services**. One such service may include the ability for you to automatically transmit Third Party Account Information to your Services profile or to automatically transmit information in your Services profile to your third party account; for example, you may be able to post work that you have accomplished on your Facebook account. We have no control over the policies and practices of third party websites or businesses as to privacy or anything else, so if you choose to take part in any transaction or service relating to an affiliated website or business, please review all such business' or websites' policies. If you are a student, we will not share your Personal Information in connection with any commercial third party transaction or service.

### Agents

_This section describes how we share information with companies and people who help us provide NoRedInk's services to you._

We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you; for example, we may use Amazon Web Services to provide server space to us. Unless we tell you differently, our agents do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us in providing the services. If you'd like a list of the companies and people to whom we are sending this information, please email [support@noredink.com](mailto:support@noredink.com).

### User Profiles and Submissions

_This section describes how we share information with other NoRedInk users._

Certain user profile information, including your name, location, and any video or image content that such user has uploaded to the Services, may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services or address your request for our services. Your account privacy settings may allow you to limit the other users who can see the Personal Information in your user profile and/or what information in your user profile is visible to others. Please remember that any content you upload to your public user profile, along with any Personal Information or content that you voluntarily disclose online in a manner other users can view (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, etc.) becomes publicly available, and can be collected and used by others. Your user name may also be displayed to other users if and when you send messages or comments or upload images or videos through the Services and other users can contact you through messages and comments. Additionally, if you sign into the Services through a third party social networking site or service, your list of “friends” and interests from that site or service may be automatically imported to the Services. Also, such “friends,” if they are also registered users of the Services, may be able to access certain non-public information you have entered in your Services user profile. Again, we do not control the policies and practices of any other third party site or service.

### Business Transfers

_This section describes how we share information if someone else takes over control of NoRedInk or if we go out of business._

We may choose to buy or sell assets. If we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, we will not transfer your Personal Information unless the buyer or acquirer (1) intends to maintain and provide the Services as a going concern and (2) becomes subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy, including providing notice and an opportunity for you to cease use of the Services before any changes to the terms of this Privacy Policy take effect.

### Protection of NoRedInk and Others

_This section describes how we might share information in other circumstances._

We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we reasonably believe is necessary to comply with law or court order; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of NoRedInk, our employees, our users, or others.

## Is Personal Information about me secure?

Your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security. If you access your account via a third party site or service, you may have additional or different sign-on protections via that third party site or service. You must prevent unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

We endeavor to protect the privacy of your account and other Personal Information we hold in our records, but unfortunately, we cannot guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time.

## What Personal Information can I access?

Through your account settings, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information you've provided to us:

  * name and password
  * email address
  * user profile information
  * gender
  * location
  * interests and preferences like favorite TV shows, celebrities, sports teams, names to be included in your sentences, etc.

If you would like to request that Children's Personal Information regarding your child (or, if you are a teacher, a child that is in your class) be updated or deleted by the Services, please contact us at [support@noredink.com](mailto:support@noredink.com). A minor student's participation in our Services, and the ability of a minor student to access the Services, will not be conditioned on that student providing more Children's Personal Information than is reasonably necessary for that participation or access. We will respond to a request made pursuant to this section within 30 days of our receipt of such request.

The information you can view, update, and delete may change as the Services change. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at [support@noredink.com](mailto:support@noredink.com).

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to [support@noredink.com](mailto:support@noredink.com).

## What choices do I have?

You can always choose not to disclose information to us, but keep in mind some information may be needed to register with us or to take advantage of some of our special features.

You may be able to add, update, or delete information as explained above. When you update information, however, we may maintain a copy of the unrevised information in our records. You may request deletion of your account by filling out [this form](https://preferences.noredink.com/privacy). Some information may remain in our records after your deletion of such information from your account. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you update or delete it, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.
